<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Searches on A Tour of Dgraph</title>
    <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Searches on A Tour of Dgraph</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:32:26 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tour.dgraph.io/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Indexes</title>
      <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:31:59 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/1/</guid>
      <description>When Dgraph is searching for strings, dates, or other values based on a filter, it needs an index to make the search efficient. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen examples of how to specify the indexes in a schema mutation.
int, float, geo and date have default indexes, but string has options of what index types to choose. Multiple indexes can be built for the same string valued predicate.
For string the following indexes are available</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Term search</title>
      <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:31:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/2/</guid>
      <description>With the term index the functions allofterms and anyofterms find strings that match all of the listed terms or any one of the listed terms. Previous queries in the tour used these searches.
Try both options and note the difference.
The query makes no further constraints than requiring the found nodes to have a name matching the terms, so actors and directors are returned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:31:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/3/</guid>
      <description>Regular expressions require the trigram index. A trigram is a substring of 3 consecutive characters, or runes.
The trigrams of trigram are: tri, rig, igr, gra and ram.
Valid regular expressions are able to be converted to a trigram query against the index. Dgraph searches the trigram index for possible matches and then runs the full regular expression against the possibles.
Each regular expressions must match at least one trigram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exact index and inequality</title>
      <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:31:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/4/</guid>
      <description>With the exact index inequalities on strings can be used in filters. Try the query after adding the exact index to the string indexes.
The hash index allows fast filtering for eq on strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Text Search</title>
      <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:31:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/5/</guid>
      <description>Full text search is what Google does for web pages. It&amp;rsquo;s different to term matching because it tries to respect language, grammar and tense. For example, matching search term run with documents containing run, running and ran.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t match terms exactly and instead makes use of
 stemming : finding a common base word so differences in tense, plural/singular or other inflection are still matched, and stop words : removing words such as and, or, it and maybe that occur too often to search over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Text Search : language support</title>
      <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:32:13 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/6/</guid>
      <description>Full text search works only for languages for which there are stemming procedures and stop word lists.
Currently, Dgraph supports
   Language Country Code     Danish da   Dutch nl   English en   Finnish fi   French fr   German de   Hungarian hu   Italian it   Norwegian no   Portuguese pt   Romanian ro   Russian ru   Spanish es   Swedish sv   Turkish tr   Chinese zh   Japanese ja   Korean ko    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geo queries : Near</title>
      <link>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 15:32:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tour.dgraph.io/search/7/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>